Dennis Mai

Full Stack Web Developer



dennismai.dev



(h) Lihue, HI 96766



469-785-2133

Freelance and Contract Web Developer, committed to improving business outcomes. I utilize my experience in business, education and programming to distill problems to their essence, collaborate with my team, and provide simple, powerful solutions with technology. I am fluent in M/ PERN stacks and have a keen eye for crafting user-centered experiences and designs.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer & Contractor

Self-Employed -- Lihue, HI

08/2018 - Present

- Strategically create and market digital campaigns for businesses and individuals
- Budget, scope, and plan projects with clear deliverables, timelines, & responsibilities
- $\ Continuously\ communicate\ and\ collaborate\ with\ stakeholders\ while\ developing\ technical\ solutions$
- + Achievements:
 - Prototyped Quiz app UI (https://www.triviaquizgame.com not maintained) using PHP, Tailwind & Javascript
 - Revised proprietary crawlers for https://www.collegeconsensus.com/ using Puppeteer in Node.js

Business Analyst - Inventory Specialist

DeinDeal AG -- Zurich, Switzerland

06/2014 - 11/2016

- Orchestrate complex operations between multiple departments for major online events and inventory management
- Gather, clean, and process raw data to optimize purchasing & sales decisions for sales potential vs. financial risk
- + Tasked with improving Inventory Turnover from 7 months to industry-appropriate benchmarks. Spear-headed major online sales events, analyzed pricing & product lifecycles, and coordinated with other departments. Drastically reduced Inventory Turnover to 3-5 months within 2 months of implementation and re-defined company category management.

Technical Skills

Frameworks & Libraries React, Redux, Apollo Client, Bootstrap, Express, Styled-Components, Tailwind Scripting Languages Javascript ES5+, Node, Typescript, Python3 Devops, Testing & Deployment Docker, Webpack, Babel, Gulp, Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library, Travis, Heroku, Netlify

(+) Markup & Style
HTML5, ejs, CSS3, SCSS,
CSS-in-JS, CSS-in-CSS

Databases PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, mySQL, Redis Design Tools

Figma, Zeplin, Gimp
Inkscape, Adobe XD

Collaboration & Productivity
Git, Github, Bitbucket, Slack,
Jira, Salesforce, Google Suite

Languages & Education

Natural Languages

Fluent Written & Verbal: English, French, Spanish Conversational: Swiss-German, German, Vietnamese

Education

Wichita State University — 2007-2012

BBA Economics 3.9 GPA
BA Spanish 3.8 GPA